A Guide to the National Committee on United States-China Relations records, RG 7, Accession 7 FA1189
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Programs, Projects and Proposals, 1966-2014; 8
  - Speakers File (C-E, M-Z), late 1960s - early 1970s (Box 16, Folder 155-159)
    Alphabetical file of China experts, including biographical details, areas of expertise, and bibliography. There are also portrait photographs of Alexander Eckstein, Franz Michael, Chester Ronning, William Allen Rusher, and James C. Thomson, Jr. A listing of experts by subject areas is found at the beginning of the file. The files for letters F-L are missing from this set.
  - Potential Speakers: General, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 160)
  - Potential Speakers: Japan, Taiwan, Hong Kong, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 161)
  - Resource Book on China, circa 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 162-163)
    Preliminary outline, drafts, and material for a book project eventually published as China: A Resource and Curriculum Guide, ed. Arlene Posner and Arne J. de Keijzer, revised edition, 1972.
- Ping Pong Diplomacy, 1971; 9
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation in the 31st World Championships: A Portfolio of Photos, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    Full title: The Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Participated in the 31st World Table Tennis Championships and Visited Japan: A Portfolio of Photos. In English and Chinese. Friendship Publishing Company, Hong Kong.
- Development, 1999, 2006; 10
  - Proposal to the U. S. Department of State Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs (Project on Increasing Public Participation in Land Use Decisions in China), 2006 February 8 (Box 10, Folder 113)
    Reference number ECA-PE-C-06-01.
  - Draft Proposal to the United States Information Agency for FY 2000, 1999 September (Box 57, Folder 570)
    Draft proposal for group exchanges, workshops, scholar orientation program, and facilitative assistance for visits of senior Chinese officials to the U. S.
- Board of Directors, Committees, and Members records, 1965-1973, 2002-2014; 11
  The Board, Committees, and Members series in RG 7 contains a set of Board meeting records and materials for 2002 - 2014 (there are no records for 2004) and of Executive Committee records for 2004 - 2014. These records complete the earlier runs of Board and Executive Committee records found in RG 5 and RG 6 (FA1187 and FA1188). The series also includes some mailings to Board members on topical issues, 1965 - 1967, and programming proposals for the early 1970s.
  - Corporate and Educational Services Proposals, 1970-1973 (Box 17, Folder 165)
    Proposals for business programs on U. S. - China Trade and for various educational programs including Field Staffs, Roaming Scholars, and others.
  - Mailings on China and the United Nations, 1965-1967 (Box 17, Folder 166)
  - Mailings on the Cultural Revolution, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 167)
  - Annual Members' Meetings, 2003, 2005-2009, 2014 (Box 17, Folder 168)
    Meeting packets with Agenda, Board slate, and Program and Financial Reports. See also the Board of Directors Meeting files.
  - Board of Directors Meetings and Materials, 2002-2003 (Box 17, Folder 169-170)
    Also includes Agenda for Annual Members' Meeting.
  - Board of Directors Meetings and Materials, 2005-2014 (Box 18, Folder 171-178)
    Also includes Agenda for Annual Members' Meeting. There is no file for 2004.
  - Executive Committee Meetings and Materials, 2004-2005 (Box 18, Folder 179-180)
  - Executive Committee Meetings and Materials, 2006-2014 (Box 19, Folder 181-188)
- HIV-AIDS, 2002-2008; 12
  The HIV-AIDS series documents exchange programs the National Committee organized between Chinese and American public-health specialists, HIV-AIDS workers, and journalists, from 2003 - 2006. In 2003, the NCUSCR sponsored a fellowship visit for three Chinese HIV-AIDS activists, who spent two months in the U. S. learning from community-level organizations engaged in education and outreach. Subsequent two-way exchange programs focused on the role of Community Planning in HIV-AIDS Policy-Making (delegation from China, October 31 - November 13, 2004) and for HIV-AIDS Prevention and Treatment in China (American specialists led workshops in Beijing and Yunnan, May 20 – June 1, 2005). A second exchange program focused on the Media's role in working to overcome stigma and discrimination and foster understanding and community engagement in the fight against HIV-AIDS. A delegation of high-level Chinese journalists visited the U. S. on a two-week study tour in the spring of 2006 (March 23 – April 7) in which they visited HIV-AIDS organizations and received special training in strategic communication techniques. The following month (May 20-31, 2006), American and Chinese specialists led journalist training workshops in Beijing, Changsha, and Guangzhou. The series also includes background readings on HIV-AIDS in China, some program materials from delegation visits and workshops, as well as information on other HIV-AIDS conferences.
  Related Materials
  Grants from the U.S. Department of State's Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs funded both the Community Planning and the Media exchange programs. Records pertaining to these grants are found in RG 6 (FA1188), Development series, boxes 30-31, folders 273-274, 276-279.
  - HIV-AIDS Education and Outreach Fellowship Program, 2003 June 28 - August 23 (Box 11, Folder 114)
    Study Tour and internship program for three HIV-AIDS educators from China. Includes Itinerary, Final Report, and program materials.
    Additional records pertaining to the HIV-AIDS Education and Outreach Fellows visit, 2003 June 28 - August 23, are found in RG 1 (FA772), Exchanges from China series, boxes 108-109, folders 1572-1576.
  - Community Planning for HIV-AIDS Prevention and Treatment in China: Program and Planning, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 115)
    Correspondence and program materials, primarily concerning the delegation to China, 2005 May 20 - June 1.
  - Community Planning for HIV-AIDS Prevention and Treatment in China: Program and Planning Book, 2004-2005 (Box 11, Folder 116)
    File contains portions of a planning binder concerning the Community Planning delegations to and from the U. S., 2004 October 31 - November 13, and 2005 May 20 - June 1.
  - HIV-AIDS and Community Planning Delegation from China: Itinerary and Delegates, 2004 October 31 - November 13 (Box 11, Folder 117)
    Includes brochure and delegate information.
  - HIV-AIDS and Community Planning Delegation from China: Itinerary and Delegates, 2004 October 31 - November 13; Digital Media: CD-RW (Box 11, Folder 117)
    Conditions of Access: Access copy currently unavailable. Researchers interested in accessing digital media in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. Please contact an archivist if you are uncertain if there is an access surrogate or to ask that one be made.
    Photos, November 2004, of SB (Escort, Shenyu Belsky) Group.
  - HIV-AIDS and Community Planning Delegation from China: Visits and Program Materials (General), 2004 October 31 - November 13 (Box 11, Folder 118)
    Hand-outs and program materials from visits to Boston, Rhode Island, Washington, DC, and Los Angeles.
  - HIV-AIDS and Community Planning Delegation from China: Los Angeles County, 2004 November 8 (Box 11, Folder 119)
    Department of Health Services, Public Health, Office of AIDS Programs and Policy. Binder on programs, educational materials, and marketing.
  - HIV-AIDS and Community Planning Delegation from China: Reach LA, 2004 November (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - HIV-AIDS and Community Planning Delegation from China: Reach LA, 2004 November; CD. (Box 11, Folder 120)
    Respect Yourself, Protect Yourself. Reach LA.
  - HIV-AIDS and Community Planning Delegation from China: Evaluations and Reports, 2004 October 31 - November 13 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Community Planning for HIV-AIDS Prevention and Treatment in China: General, 2005 May 20 - June 1 (Box 12, Folder 122)
  - Community Planning for HIV-AIDS Prevention and Treatment in China: Briefing Book, 2005 May 20 - June 1 (Box 12, Folder 123-124)
  - Community Planning for HIV-AIDS Prevention and Treatment in China: Evaluations, 2005 May 20 - June 1 (Box 12, Folder 125)
  - Community Planning for HIV-AIDS Prevention and Treatment in China: Reports and Follow-Up, 2005 May 20 - June 1 (Box 12, Folder 126)
  - Community Planning for HIV-AIDS Prevention and Treatment in China: Reports and Follow-Up, 2005 May 20 - June 1; Still Images: 4" x 6" prints: 13 color and 14 black and white (27 total). Retained in file. (Box 12, Folder 126)
    Photos of workshop participants and presentations.
  - Developing Effective Media Campaigns for HIV-AIDS Education in China: Background and Planning, 2003-2004 (Box 12, Folder 127)
    Project also described as "Developing Effective Media Reporting."
  - HIV-AIDS and the Media in China: General, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 128)
    Includes program evaluations by Media delegation from China, 2006 March 25 - April 7, and report on Journalist Training Workshops in China, May 20-31.
  - HIV- AIDS and the Media in China: Program and Planning, 2003, 2005-2006 (Box 12, Folder 129)
    Correspondence and materials. File includes some correspondence concerning 2003 study delegation, but mainly concerns 2006 May 20-31 delegation to China.
  - HIV-AIDS and the Media in China: Program and Planning Book, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 130-131)
    File contains portions of a planning binder concerning the Media delegation from China, 2006 March 25 - April 7, and the Journalist Training Workshops in China, May 20-31.
  - HIV-AIDS and the Media in China: Background Materials, 2006 May 20-31 (Box 13, Folder 132)
    Journalist Training Workshops.
  - HIV-AIDS and the Media in China: Delegates, 2006 May 20-31 (Box 13, Folder 133)
  - HIV-AIDS and the Media in China: Program Booklets, 2006 May 20-31 (Box 13, Folder 134)
    Includes powerpoint slides and outlines of presentations. Also includes program for High Level Seminar on AIDS Reporting, May 22-24, at Tsinghua University (in Chinese).
  - Tsinghua University, Media Workshop on HIV-AIDS, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 135)
    Program materials from two unidentified workshops.
  - HIV-AIDS Programs and Information (General), 2004-2007 (Box 13, Folder 136)
    Papers, articles, and programs, pertaining mainly to China. Includes response to final report questionnaire for the HIV-AIDS Education and Outreach Fellows (from China), circa 2003.
  - Asian and Pacific Islander Communities in the US and China: HIV- AIDS Conference, 2006 November 13 (Box 13, Folder 137)
    Persistent Challenges and Promising Future. Conference organized by Chinese-American Planning Council, Inc., Chinese AIDS Fund, Inc., and New York University School of Medicine Center for AIDS Research.
  - HIV-AIDs and the Blood Supply (Proposed Workshop), 2007-2008 (Box 13, Folder 138)
  - Research on HIV-AIDS in China (Janie Hsieh), circa 2005 (Box 14, Folder 139)
  - Directory of HIV-AIDS NGOs in China, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 140)
  - Background Information and Research, 2003-2007 (Box 14, Folder 141-143)
    Reports and Articles on HIV-AIDS in China. Folder 141 also includes program materials (literature and powerpoint slides) from the HIV-AIDS Community Planning Delegation's visits in May 2005 to the Chinese Center for Disease Control and to the Yunnan Reproductive Health Research Association.
  - Background Information and Literature, 2004-2007 (Box 14, Folder 144-145)
    Mainly on HIV-AIDS in Asia and China. Includes several issues of the China CIPRA Newsletter (China Integrated Programs for Research on AIDS).
  - Background Readings - Media Coverage of HIV-AIDS, 2002-2006 (Box 14, Folder 146)
  - Background Readings - Media Coverage of HIV-AIDS, 2003-2006 (Box 15, Folder 147)
  - New Briefing Materials, 2005-2007 (Box 15, Folder 148)
- America-China Society / America-China Forum Programs and Staff, 1986-2002; 13
  The America-China Society (ACS) was founded in 1987 by Henry Kissinger and Cyrus Vance with the goal of promoting understanding and cooperation between the People's Republic of China and the United States. Kissinger and Vance co-chaired the organization, which consisted of 35-40 Directors – business executives or former government leaders – who shared interest in China. According to its statement of purpose, "the America-China Society works to increase understanding between the United States and the PRC; to advance diplomatic, commercial, cultural, social, scientific and educational ties; to foster public policies which promote their shared interests; to enhance opportunities for United States enterprises to engage in mutually beneficial investment and trade with the PRC; and to cooperate with governmental and private organizations having comparable objectives." In January 2000, the ACS directors voted to merge with the National Committee, becoming (around 2001), the America-China Forum of the National Committee on U. S. – China Relations.
  The ACS/ACF records in this series consist of Executive Directors correspondence, 1988 – 1999; Directors correspondence, late 1980s – 1990s, and correspondence with Individuals, mid- to late 1990s; organizational records and meeting minutes and materials, 1986 – 2000; records of ACS programs and events; ACS Trip files; and various office files. While some of the meeting, trip, and event files include remarks or notes by Kissinger, materials in the correspondence files pertaining to Kissinger consist mainly of informational memos to him (with marginal responses) or prepared letters.
  - Executive Director Chronological Files (Mary Wadsworth-Darby), 1988 January-August (Box 20, Folder 199-201)
  - Executive Director Chronological Files (Mary Wadsworth-Darby), 1988 September - 1989, 1992 January-September (Box 21, Folder 202-208)
  - Executive Director Chronological Files (Mary Wadsworth-Darby), 1992 October - 1993 August (Box 22, Folder 209-214)
  - Executive Director Chronological Files (Mary Wadsworth-Darby), 1993 September - 1994 August (Box 23, Folder 215-218)
    Mary Wadsworth-Darby left the ACS as of August 1994.
  - Executive Director Memos to Henry Kissinger (Mary Wadsworth-Darby), 1988-1989 June (Box 23, Folder 219-220)
  - Executive Director Memos to Henry Kissinger (Mary Wadsworth-Darby), 1989 July -1993 (Box 24, Folder 221-228)
  - Shanghai Communique Commemoration - Planning File, 1992 January-April (Box 25, Folder 229-230)
    Executive Director Mary Wadsworth-Darby. Twentieth Anniversary of the Shanghai Communique. Delegation and visit of Shanghai Mayor Huang Ju, 1992 April 27 - May 7. Invitations, schedule, dinner. ACS Board Meeting and Symposium, 1992 April 30. Memos and correspondence.
  - America-China Society Symposium, 1992 April 30 (Box 25, Folder 231)
    Symposium held in conjunction with the Twentieth Anniversary of the Shanghai Communique Commemoration.
  - Executive Director Chronological Files (Herbert Levin), 1994 September - 1995 August (Box 25, Folder 232-235)
    Herbert Levin began as executive director on October 1, 1994.
  - Executive Director Chronological Files (Herbert Levin), 1995 September - 1997 February (Box 26, Folder 236-242)
  - Executive Director Chronological Files (Herbert Levin), 1997 March - 1999 (Box 27, Folder 243-246)
  - Herbert Levin Memos to Henry Kissinger, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 247-249)
    Informational memos from the executive director.
  - Herbert Levin Memos to Henry Kissinger, 1996-1998 March (Box 28, Folder 250-255)
  - Herbert Levin Memos to Henry Kissinger, 1998 April - 1999 (Box 29, Folder 256-258)
  - Henry Kissinger Responses to Informational Memos, 1996-1997 (Box 29, Folder 259)
    Memos from Executive Director Herbert Levin.
  - America-China Society Articles of Incorporation and Bylaws, 1986-1988 (Box 29, Folder 260)
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1987-1997 (Box 29, Folder 261)
    There are no minutes for 1993.
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 1987 July 28 (Box 29, Folder 262)
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 1988-1990 (Box 29, Folder 263)
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 1989 May 24 (Box 29, Folder 264)
  - America-China Society Board of Directors and Discussion Meeting, 1991 January 15 - October 22 (Box 29, Folder 265)
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting and Symposium, 1992 April 30 (Box 30, Folder 266)
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting and Roundtable Discussion, 1994 January 6 (Box 30, Folder 267)
    File includes readings and a transcript of the roundtable discussion. There are small differences in the transcript compared to the copy in box 36, folder 328.
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 1994 March 7 (Box 30, Folder 268)
    Breakfast meeting.
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 1995 January 18 (Box 30, Folder 269-272)
    Agenda, Memos to Henry Kissinger, Topics and Issues, New Board Member Bios, Follow-Up Mailings. Responses and Guest Invitations. Presenters. Arrangements and Expenses.
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 1996 January 23 (Box 30, Folder 273)
    Agenda, Board book, Directors invitations and responses. Presenters and Guests. Arrangements and expenses.
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 1996 January 23 (Box 31, Folder 274-275)
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 1997 January 28 (Box 31, Folder 276-279)
    General, Program Book, Presenters and Guests, Arrangements and Planning.
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 1998 February 10 (Box 31, Folder 280)
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 1998 February 10 (Box 32, Folder 281-283)
    Presenters and Guests, Arrangements and Planning.
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 1999 January 26 (Box 32, Folder 284-287)
    Meeting booklet, correspondence, speakers, planning and arrangements.
  - America-China Society Board of Directors Meeting, 2000 January 25 (Box 33, Folder 288-289)
    Meeting booklet, correspondence, speakers, planning and arrangements. Includes notes on the discussion by David M. Albert, and copies of board meeting agendas for 1994-1999. The America-China Society Board voted at its January 25, 2000, meeting to merge with the NCUSCR and become the America-China Forum of the National Committee.
  - America-China Society Financial Statements and Contributions, 1999-2001 (Box 33, Folder 290)
  - America-China Forum Meeting, 2001 June 20 (Box 33, Folder 291)
    The America-China Society Board voted at its January 25, 2000, meeting to merge with the NCUSCR and become the America-China Forum of the National Committee.
  - America-China Forum Delegation to China, 2001 March 18-23 (Box 33, Folder 292-294)
    Trip originally planned for December 2000, but postponed.
  - Press Conference Announcing Formation of America-China Society, 1987 March 24 (Box 33, Folder 295)
  - Henry Kissinger China Trip, 1987 September (Box 33, Folder 296)
  - China Study Group Response Letters, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 297)
    Responses concerning experiences of American corporations in doing business in China.
  - U. S. - China Economic Symposium, 1988 July 15-17 (Box 34, Folder 298)
    Includes Briefing meeting held June 22 and/or June 24. Also described as CITIC (China International Trust Investment Corporation) conference.
  - Dinners for Xu Jiatun and Foreign Minister Qian Qichen, 1988 August 10 and September 28 (Box 34, Folder 299)
    Xu Jiatun was director of the Xinhua News Agency in Hong Kong.
  - America-China Society Conference, 1989 May 23-24 (Box 34, Folder 300-302)
    "China, the U. S. and the Future of Asia," Washington, DC. Includes speeches and proceedings.
  - Li Huichuan Delegation, 1989 May 22 - June 8 (Box 34, Folder 303)
    The delegation was in New York from May 27 - June 2.
  - Henry Kissinger China Trip, 1989 November (Box 34, Folder 304)
    Notes on trip and discussions by Mary Wadsworth-Darby.
  - Fundraising and Contributions, 1988-1989 (Box 34, Folder 305)
  - America-China Society Breakfast Meeting, 1990 June 7 (Box 34, Folder 306)
  - America-China Society Breakfast, 1990 July 11 (Box 34, Folder 307)
    Delegation of Chinese Mayors. Includes memo on status of MFN issue. July 3.
  - America-China Society Meeting, 1990 July 25 (Box 34, Folder 308)
  - America-China Society Trip to China, 1990 September (Box 34, Folder 309)
    Includes transcripts of discussions.
  - America-China Society Meeting and Huang Hua Delegation, 1991 January (Box 34, Folder 310)
    ACS Board of Directors and Discussion Meeting, 1991 January 15, attended by Huang Hua, former Foreign Minister and Vice Chair of the People's Congress. The delegation visited the U. S. from January 14 - February 1, 1991. File includes transcript of January 15 meeting.
  - America-China Society Breakfast Meeting, 1991 June 21 (Box 34, Folder 311)
    Meetings with Chinese participants in the NCUSCR's Fifth U. S. - China Dialogue, 1991 June 12-23.
  - Mary Wadsworth-Darby Memos to Henry Kissinger, 1991 January-June (Box 34, Folder 312)
  - America-China Society Trip to China, 1991 September 7-10 (Box 35, Folder 313-314)
  - America-China Society Breakfast Meeting (Zhang Wenpu), 1992 November 19 (Box 35, Folder 315)
  - Henry Kissinger Trip to China (Pacific Enterprises Group Corp.), 1992 December (Box 35, Folder 316)
    Invitation to speak at factory opening in Zhanjiang.
  - America-China Society Roundtable Discussion Meeting, 1992 December 15 (Box 35, Folder 317)
  - Economic Development Seminar, Chongqing, 1993 April 19-21 (Box 35, Folder 318)
    Mary Wadsworth-Darby attended.
  - Economic Development Seminar, Chongqing, 1993 April 19-21; Still Image: Color 7"x 10" print. (Box 35, Folder 318)
    Groupphoto of seminar participants.
  - Chen Yuan Luncheon, 1993 May 5 (Box 35, Folder 319)
    Chen Yuan was deputy governor, People's Bank of China.
  - America-China Society Delegation to China, 1993 May 14-19 (Box 35, Folder 320-321)
    Program, briefing book, and meeting notes. The meetings took place May 16-18, 1993.
  - U.N. Conference on International Cooperation to Promote Conversion from Military to Civilian Industry, Hong Kong, 1993 July 7-11 (Box 35, Folder 322-323)
    Conference sponsored by the U. N. and the China Association for Peaceful Use of Military and Industrial Technology. Mary Wadsworth-Darby chaired the working session on international cooperation.
  - Beijing Conference on the Prospects for East Asian Cooperation and Development, 1993 July (Box 35, Folder 324)
  - America-China Society Germany Trip, 1993 October (Box 35, Folder 325)
    File contains miscellaneous correspondence concerning Mary Wadsworth-Darby trip.
  - America-China Society Breakfast Meeting (Liu Shuqing), 1993 October 20 (Box 35, Folder 326)
    China People's Institute of Foreign Affairs Delegation, 1993 October 15-30. Includes notes on discussion October 18, 1993.
  - America-China Society Dinner (Yang Jiechi), 1993 November 6 (Box 36, Folder 327)
    Dinner hosted by Mary Wadsworth-Darby.
  - America-China Society Roundtable Discussion Meeting (Transcript), 1994 January 6 (Box 36, Folder 328)
  - America-China Society Breakfast Meeting (Ambassador Li Luye), 1994 February 22 (Box 36, Folder 329)
    China Center for International Studies Delegation.
  - Song Jian, Chinese Government Science and Technology Delegation, Visit, 1994 April (Box 36, Folder 330)
  - Individual Correspondence and Contacts, A, 1995-1997 (Box 36, Folder 331)
    Individual Correspondence and Contacts
  - Individual Correspondence and Contacts, B, 1995-1999 (Box 36, Folder 332)
  - Individual Correspondence and Contacts, A. Doak Barnett, 1991-1999 (Box 36, Folder 333)
    Includes papers and articles.